# DONNIE HICKS

# **FULL STACK DEVELOPER\***

### Summary

I completed a History degree with highest honours before working in communications and sales for the second largest telecom in the world. After relocating to Canada I continued as a professional communicator at the City of Toronto for nearly a decade as an Advanced Emergency Medical Dispatcher. Wishing to grow beyond that role and inspired by the potential of working with software professionally, I transformed my hobby in computers into a career as a Full Stack Developer.

### Goal

I am seeking a positive work environment that appreciates my broad skillset and diverse experience, and gives me an opportunity to work with Javascript, React and GraphQL. I am particularly interested in writing code using the Functional Programming paragidigm, and generating blazing-fast, static, low maintence, secure web applications with the JAMStack or Serverless architecture.

# **Employment**

Hyxos Toronto

### Cofounder/Full Stack Developer

March 2013 to Current

In 2013 I cofounded Hyxos Inc. with my wife in order to pursue business projects. In our most recent endeavor I designed and produced the first edition of a card game called TZI using Python to programmatically generate image assets. I created our product website by coding in Javascript and using the Gatsby static site generator library, utilizing React components and querying content data through the GraphQL API.

## The Brewbox Company

**Toronto** 

## Full Stack Developer

# September 2016 to March 2017

For email marketing purposes I organized and automated the process of syncronizing customer data with Mailchimp through their API. I worked with Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL and Javascript to maintain and extend administrative and other backend support features of the company web portal.

# The City of Toronto

**Toronto** 

### Advanced Emergency Medical Dispatcher

Sept. 2006 to Oct. 2015

Following established medical protocols, I determined the prioritization of incoming 911 calls and administered first-aid and CPR instructions over the phone. Through radio and telephone channels I dispatched ambulances crews and strategically managed departmental resources to ensure paramedic safety and produce optimal patient outcomes.

# AT&T (formerly SBC)

Tulsa, Oklahoma

### Billing Specialist

# September 2002 to May 2003

Fielding inbound calls regarding billing questions, I explained policies, billing procedures, and presented product offerings as solutions to customer needs based on personalized profiles.

# **Projects**

#### www.tzi.cards

### **February 2019 to Current**

A card game inspired by the lunar calendar. TZI Cards reimagines traditional playing cards and explores the ancient Chinese system of Heavenly Stems and Earthly branches. I built the product home page using the Gatsby static site generator library, and deployed it through Netlify. I also designed and produced all of the digital art assets for the product and site.

#### 1hx.ca

#### October 2009 to Current

A short-link generator based on YOURLS. I have used open source software to keep this personal project alive and running on the internet for almost ten years. Originally served on a shared hosting platform, I have migrated it through different backend configurations multiple times. Currently running on Ubuntu in a VPS, routing through Nginx, SSL through letsencrypt, and data storage with MySQL.

### **Contact**

donnie@hyxos.ca

416-878-4790

**♥** Toronto, Ontario, Canada

in donniehicks

**y** macbraughton

hyxos

### **Education**

Oral Roberts University

Sept. 1997 to May 2001

### Bachelor's of History 2001

3.97 GPA Summa Cum Laude Academic Peer Advisor Minors: Philsophy, Modern Hebrew

Lighthouse Oct. to Dec. Labs 2015

#### Web Development Bootcamp

Ruby on Rails PostgreSQL Javascript

Advanced Analytics Jan. and Research Lab 2018

#### Citizen Data Scientist I - III

Introduction to Data Science R Programming Language

#### Skills

#### **Frontend**

HTML CSS/SCSS/SASS Markup

#### **Programming Languages**

Javascript Python Ruby

#### Libraries

Gatsby React GraphQL

#### **Frameworks**

Rails Django

#### **Backend**

Linux/Unix PostgreSQL/MySQL/SQLite MongoDB SSL/TLS

#### **Hobbies**

Playing Guitar and Drums Singing and Songwriting Playing Video and Board Games Bee-Keeping